y'all, this week we're starting to
dive into Excel a little bit more
and adding a little bit more
complexity to it. And I use complexity
really lightly because once you
do one or two practice problems,
you're going to get it, no problem.
It's pretty straightforward, but
with referencing other cells and
summary statistics, these are honestly
things that I use every time I
open up Excel. And I know a lot of
you asked that question in the
welcome survey of what tips and tricks
and tools should you understand and
honestly being able to know where
to put a dollar sign when you're
referencing a cell is going to be one
of the most handy things you can
learn. Again I use it every time I
open up Excel and what it does is it
ends up locking things into place.
So one of the main functionalities
in Excel is for you to reference
another cell meaning if something is
likely to change you don't have to
go in and change the underlying
number for the next quarter you can
just reference where the calculated
answer comes out and plug it in and
so your spreadsheet's going to
stay always up to date and so being
able to know where to lock a cell
into place so as you move a formula
around then it will stay the calculation
will stay as you expect it to.
So really pay attention to the reference
part of this week's assignments.
Then you're also going to work
through summary statistics. And the
summary statistics are also super
invaluable. It's one of the things I
use really regularly. A lot of
business questions can be answered
through aggregation, or in this case,
something called summary statistics.
It's figuring out where your middle
of your data is, that's your average,
what your biggest number is, what
your smallest number are, and how
much spread is in your data. So
we're going to be really looking at
these summary statistics, which are
going to be super helpful for you,
not only in this class, but in
future classes as well. And then
you're also going to be doing some
financial formulas. So these are
things like calculating a rent
payment or a mortgage payment or what
your rate would be. So not only
are these going to be applicable
if you're going into a more financial
oriented world, but they have
direct impact on your daily life
because then you can start to run
different scenarios and say, okay,
how much can I expect a mortgage
payment to be if I put X amount
down, what are the different fees
that I can expect to pay? And
then what is that going, my total
monthly payment going to look like?
So we can start to really think
through how this has a broader
applicability, not just to you right
now in your coursework, but
tangibly in your life. So as always,
enjoy. Let me know if
there's anything I can do to
help as you work through
these practice problems, and
I will see you in our
context and concept lessons.